For me, it was bacon.
对我来说，这是培根。
There I was, standing in the streets of Medellin, Colombia, looking hungrily at a delicious empanada.
当时我正站在哥伦比亚麦德林的街头，饥肠辘辘地盯着一份美味的肉馅卷饼。
The sign read 'queso y tocino'.
招牌上写着“queso y tocino”。
Because I'd got my tongue round some essential Spanish vocabulary, I knew that 'queso' was cheese.
因为我已经掌握了一些基础的西班牙语词汇，所以知道“queso”是奶酪的意思。
But 'tocino'?
可“tocino”是什么呢？
I typed it into my smartphone translation app. What came back? 'Tocino'.
我在手机翻译软件里输入了这个词，结果出来的还是“tocino”。
I later learned that means 'bacon' in the local lingo.
后来我才知道，这个词在当地方言中就是“培根”的意思。
Computer-assisted translation is popular.
计算机辅助翻译如今十分普及。
Google Translate, for example, is used by more than 500 million people.
比如谷歌翻译的用户就超过5亿人。
But while convenient and easy to use, they are hardly perfect.
尽管这类工具方便易用，却远非尽善尽美。
Now, dropping the odd expression now and again is hardly important on an informal conversational level – as might happen to a tourist on holiday.
在非正式的日常对话中，偶尔翻错一两个表达其实无伤大雅——就像度假游客遇到的情况那样。
But in more formal circumstances, such as a medical or legal discussion, the wrong vernacular can be disastrous.
但在更正式的场合，比如医疗问诊或法律谈判中，用错术语可能会引发灾难性的后果。
So, can a computer translator ever equal a human?
那么，计算机翻译到底能不能媲美人工翻译哪？
The technology has come a long way.
这项技术已经取得了长足的进步。
These days, people can wear a 'translation earpiece'. These pick up the foreign terminology and translate it directly to the wearer.
如今人们可以佩戴“翻译耳机”，这种设备能捕捉到外语，并直接翻译给佩戴者。
Andrew Ochoa, chief executive of US start-up Waverly Labs, a producer of one such earpiece, says they work by 'combining a network of algorithms and speech-recognition technology'. But they have limitations.
美国初创公司韦弗利实验室就生产这类耳机，其首席执行官安德鲁·奥乔亚表示，这种耳机的工作原理是“将算法网络与语音识别技术相结合”。
Firstly, there's a delay while the phrase is translated.
但这类设备也存在局限性。
How long often depends on the connection strength.
首先，翻译外语时会有延迟，延迟时长通常取决于信号强度。
Secondly, they aren't able to communicate human sentiment well.
其次，它们无法很好地传达人类的情感。
Human conversation is subtler than just the words used.
人类的对话远比词句本身要精妙。
It has tone, attitude, nuance, for example.
比如对话中还包含语气、态度和细微的含义差别。
"If you want to create a relationship… you need a human translator to make it sound natural,"
全球营销翻译机构词库公司的品牌内容总监佐伊·库珀在接受BBC采访时说：“如果你想建立良好的沟通关系……
Zoey Cooper, brand and content director at Wordbank, a global marketing and translation agency, told the BBC.
就需要人工翻译来让表达听起来自然地道。”
So, while many professional translators do use computer-assisted translation tools to help them with the repetitive nature of translation, context is important.
因此，尽管许多专业翻译人员确实会借助计算机辅助翻译工具来处理翻译工作中重复性的部分，但语境至关重要。
It might work well for a survey or instruction manual, but for important human-to-human speech, and for the time being at least, better to use a translator, or your message might get garbled or lost in translation.
这类工具或许适用于翻译调查问卷或说明书，但至少目前来说，在重要的人际对话中，最好还是请人工翻译，否则你的信息可能会被曲解，或是在翻译过程中丢失原意。